column_heading_in_crop_origins_v_1_0	key_for_column_headings
id	crop species id number
common_name_crop	common name of crop species
species_name	crop taxon binomial
species_name_taxonstand_	"complete scientific name of the crop taxon with ""_"" as space delimitator"
species_name_	"crop taxon binomial with ""_"" as space delimitator"
genus	crop taxon genus
sps	crop taxon specific epithet
family	crop taxon family
order	crop taxon order
gf	growth form (either herb, woody, or graminoid)
wild_progenitor	most likely wild progenitor(s) of the crop 
sources_wild_progenitor	literature sources used to ascribe identity of wild progenitor (numbers are the labels of entries in sources_crop_origins_1_0.txt Bibtext file)
minimum_time_cultivation	earliest evidence of explotation under cultivation (y.a.)
minimum_time_domestication	earliest evidence of domestication (y.a.)
sources_minimum_time_cultivation_domestication	literature sources used to find out data on antiquity of cultivation and domestication (numbers are the labels of entries in sources_crop_origins_1_0.txt Bibtext file)
filter_data_antiquity	whether data of antiquity of a crop species is (1) or is not (0) available.
use_food	whether a crop species is (1) or is not (0) a source of food for humans
use_animal_feed	whether a crop species is (1) or is not (0) a source of feed for livestock
use	non-exclusive types of use of each crop (either food&forage, forage,fruit_or_flowers,multifood_reproductive,multifood_reproductive_and_vegetative,multifood_vegetative,root, seed, vegetative_shoot)
use_primary	either the only type of use (forage, fruit_or_flowers, root, seed, vegetative_shoot) of the crop, or the one that is agriculturally more relevant
sources_use	literature sources used to find out data on type of use of crop species (numbers are the labels of entries in sources_crop_origins_1_0.txt Bibtext file)
number_gbif_records	number of individual occurrences in GBIF for the wild progenitor(s) of the crop
filter_ocurr_gbif	whether data of geographic distribution of a crop wild progenitors is (1) or is not (0) available.
sd_longitude	Standard Deviation of geographic longitude (decimal degrees) of the GBIF occurrences of the wild progenitor
sd_latitude	Standard Deviation of geographic latitude (decimal degrees) of the GBIF occurrences of the wild progenitor
mode_ecoreg_code	code of the ecoregion (Olson et al 2001. Bioscience 51: 933-938) where the wild progenitor(s) of a given crop inhabit more frequently
biogeografic_realm	biogeographic realm (Afrotropic, Australasia, Indo_malay, Nearctic, Neotropic, or Palearctic) of the modal ecoregion of each crop´s wild progenitor(s)
mode_ecoreg_name	name of the ecoregion (Olson et al 2001. Bioscience 51: 933-938) where the wild progenitor(s) of a given crop inhabit more frequently
mode_ecoreg_centroid_lon	geographic longitude (decimal degrees) of the centroid of the ecoregion (Olson et al 2001. Bioscience 51: 933-938) where the wild progenitor(s) of a given crop inhabit more frequently
mode_ecoreg_centroid_lat	geographic latitude (decimal degrees) of the centroid of the ecoregion (Olson et al 2001. Bioscience 51: 933-938) where the wild progenitor(s) of a given crop inhabit more frequently
median_BIO1	median of Annual Mean Temperature (ºCx10) at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO2	median of Mean Diurnal Range (Mean of monthly (max temp - min temp),ºCx10) at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO3	median of Isothermality (BIO2/BIO7) (* 100) at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO4	median of Temperature Seasonality (standard deviation *100, ºCx10) at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO5	median of Max Temperature of Warmest Month, ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO6	median of Min Temperature of Coldest Month, ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO7	median of Temperature Annual Range (BIO5-BIO6), ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO8	median of Mean Temperature of Wettest Quarter, ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO9	median of Mean Temperature of Driest Quarter, ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO10	median of Mean Temperature of Warmest Quarter,ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO11	median of Mean Temperature of Coldest Quarter, ºCx10 at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO12	median of Annual Precipitation, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO13	median of Precipitation of Wettest Month, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO14	median of Precipitation of Driest Month, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO15	median of Precipitation Seasonality (Coefficient of Variation) at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO16	median of Precipitation of Wettest Quarter, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO17	median of Precipitation of Driest Quarter, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO18	median of Precipitation of Warmest Quarter, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
median_BIO19	median of Precipitation of Coldest Quarter, mm at the geographic occurrences of the wild progenitor(s) of each crop species
